Please introduce yourself.
Hello I'm the key friendly figure in implant field. Iam professor Park Chang Jo of "maxillofacial surgery" Hanyang university hospital.
I am the director of master of course basic. I'll try to explain so that you can easily understand and I will repeat.
Important things over and over so that you can remember based on the established information and I will also cover trendy information and I will also use my trait of being kind to share the information with you.
Hello, I am Professor Park Chang Jo, "oral maxillofacial surgery" Hanyang university hospital.
Today so many things changes so rapidly every day we are bombarded by new stuff. So if you talk about the basic things you may be regarded as an outdated person radiology is the case in point in dentistry.
It is performed as a daily routine. So relatively it is considered as trivial not very important but when it comes to studying implantology we need to record diagnose and interpret each and every individual patient's situation.
So its importance cannot be overemphasized. Today I will be presenting radiology the basic image taking and interpretation. So let's have a look at the contents first.
One, dental computer tomography or cone-beam computed tomography. Two, panorama which you already know well three the standard or standard periapical radiology procedure.
First cone beam computed tomography. It is abbreviated to cbct the imaging equipment or the images.
Let's compare it to the conventional city in the case of conventional city like this very thin fan shaped x-rays are integrated step by step. In the meanwhile cone beam city uses very thick ice cream cone-shaped x-rays.
So in a short period of time finer information can be acquired. Coney's ice cream cone therefore it is named cone beam ct. The advantage is the equipment has become compact so it occupies less space.
Two, finer cuts of images can be acquired. Finer images are the basis. Therefore the information has become more accurate. Four, the x-ray beams are exposed all at once.
Therefore the exposure of radiation to patient has become drastically lowered. It has become more compact finer images more accurate and the radiation exposure is reduced greatly.
If you look at this case, young male patient he has an aggressive periodontitis. All teeth will be extracted and implants will be placed.
However the condition of teeth in the bone is very poor. As you can see complicated procedures will be done at the same time. Immediate placement is the trend today. However in this case extraction will be done and the gbr will be done in stages for the implant treatment.
Pre-OP maxilla and mandible.
There are residual teeth but they have severe mobility and the condition is not very good. Therefore we decided to remove all of them this is immediate post-OP clinical pictures. Comparing pre-OP to post-doc. Can you guess what procedures have been conducted in the meanwhile?
Pre-OP Panoramic View. Panorama image taking will be explained shortly. The most basic procedure I believe you already know about this. With just a panorama picture, will you be able to sufficiently plan for the surgery?
Therefore city can complement that. City has the three-dimensional views more accurate and the final surgery plan can be established cone beam ct is the basis and on the panorama, surgical plan is established.
From the right lower jaw a block bone will be taken and crafted in various places. Guided bone regeneration procedure will be done at the extracted sites at bilateral upper posterior areas.
A large scale sinus lifting will be done with only panorama pictures. This kind of surgical planning is not possible. With the cbct images this kind of surgical plan was able to be established.
So the advancement of cbct pushed the development of implantology as well. Post-OP picture looks like something has changed. Let's look at what has changed. First, large scale bilateral sinus lifting has been done because the patient had very thin residual bone at the upper posterior areas.
After extraction, where implant will be placed in the future. Gbr guided bone regeneration procedure was done. The round thing around the things are the bone tags to fix the membrane they appear on the x-ray like this and the patient.
In this patient the blood bone was taken from the lower posterior and that is divided and grafted to the upper left posterior and bilateral posteriors in the lower jaw.
Very complicated procedure it was difficult to do all of these at once. But thanks to cbct, cone beam ct the surgery could proceed very smoothly and easily. The treatment outcome can be checked with cbct as well.
In the past panorama had limitations in predicting the treatment outcome or complications. Using the cbct, the issue was addressed and accurate evaluations can be done with the cbct. Advancement of cbct pushed the advancement of implantology as well.
Pre-OP, post-OP panorama pictures. Please compare them in pre-OP, post-OP cone beam city images. They can be compared what have changed three-dimensionally.
How important anatomical structures remain intact. Cone beam ct cuts have been recomposed for panoramic view. So panorama view is made of cbct cuts.
The craft positions and amount can be checked. Important anatomical structure, the status of sinus and inferior inferior alveolar nerve. The location and interrelation with other structures can be definitely checked with the cbct. Cbct development has led the implantology surgical field as well.
Cbct is the key to the successful implant surgery. I can say that for sure, as you know the conspicuous trend in implantology is digital. If you do not know about digital you may not be able to join the hard discussions interaural scanning is done to acquire information of the oral situation.
The information can be put together. Three-dimensional more accurate information can be used for the digitally guided implant surgery. There are programs to plan for such surgery. I believe you have heard about this many times but,
Such planning digitally guided implanted surgery. Planning requires a cbct as a must implant this studio is used quite widely to replace that. Austin is a developing one guide clinic it is under better testing right now. If you look at here digitally guided implanted surgery the most important thing when it comes to that is the city information, city, cone beam city.
Without cbct, digitally guided implant surgery is not possible. The most important information is provided by cbct to the digitally guided surgery.
After the virtual planning, this solicitor surgery can be done using this one guide kit. It is already prepared.
For sinus lift surgery one cask kit is absolutely necessary and for placing thin implant. One ms kit is ready. So all those three kits are available and those three kits will be integrated into one guided system.
A clinical case a rather old male patient rpd the partial dentures are worn by the patient on both jaws and the patient doesn't want to wear them anymore.
In this case one guide and one cas which is dedicated for sinus lift can be used to provide comfortable and easy full mouth implant rehabilitation that's what was done pre-OP. The remaining teeth will be extracted but that will be utilized. This is one guide template mounted on the mouth.
Template guide or sometimes it's called the stent. The tool has holes to guide the drilling after the drilling implant the fixture placement can be guided. So this is the key to the guided surgery.
Using the template holes. Drillings will be guided and the implants will be placed. The initial stability was good so healing abutments are connected. In most clinical cases healing abutments are connected. Pre-OP teeth are extracted and eight implants on the maxilla.
Eight on the mandible were placed in a simple easier and accurate way. So the digitally guided implanted surgery was performed. If you compare pre-OP and post-OP.
Such a digitally-guided implanted surgery. What enabled that? right, cbct or kun bim city made it possible without that this guided surgery cannot be performed. The advancement of a cbct led the development of implanted surgery. So thus cbct is a very important radiological procedure.
The next topic is panoramic radiology. This machine is used to take the panoramic images. The advantages of them, first broad coverage can be observed, Broad coverage is enabled. Two, low radiation in a relative term. Three, the image taken can be done very simply and quickly. That's one of the biggest advantages of panorama.
Panorama radiology is the basis for implant study. Once you take panorama pictures, further procedures, further images, further radiographs can be decided. So this is the basic information very important information.
Another thing in Korea, cbct is very widely actively used. But in other countries excluding Korea, still panorama is used quite a lot for implant surgery.
Therefore, this is the basic basis of panorama surgery. That's the advantage of using panorama. A long time ago when I was a resident in oral "mix    " of surgery department. I had to do things with the panorama picture.
Over the panorama, transparent panorama paper was laid teeth and important and atomic structures were indicated and their relationship was identified. What was that? It's called tracing, tracing of panorama radiograph. Through the tracing process, through panorama broad scanning results from panorama.
We could identify teeth jaws maxillary sinuses and inferior alveolar canal. The locations were identified or relative relations were identified as well.
and more importantly through the panorama pictures. The bone height where implants would be placed later could be identified. There was the big purpose of using the tracing panorama x-ray or panorama radiology.
Over that tracing was done. This was an implant patient. On the panoramic view, transparent paper was laid with a sharp pencil the pictures were drawn. What was it called tracing?
Through the tracing on the panorama pictures. We identify the important things. First, maxillary sinuses the location, borders, and the condition of the sinuses were identified and therefore lower jaw surgery very important anatomic structure. Inferior alveolar canals location in relation to adjacent teeth.
And the height of defective bone were identified. Important anatomical structures were identified using the tracing.
I hope you understand the purpose of using tracing. The defective region's bone height can be measured as I said. They are not measured just with a ruler.
X-ray template used for that purpose. In Korea digital trend is very strong today. So bone height can be measured with the program but still in many other countries x-ray template is in use. As you can see, various implant diameters.
and various lengths per diameter are indicated here. For example, 3.5 diameter 8.5 millimeter length. Implant is here, for another example 4.5 diameter, 10 millimeter long implant looks like this.
The fixtures shown on the x-ray template are not the actual sizes. As it is indicated here, it is 125 percent bigger than the actual size. 25% amplification is done here, why?
I believe you know, but because of panorama is a spread out picture. Therefore inevitable image distortions occur. The image size is changed from the original size.
If you compare horizontal and vertical changes. Vertical distortions, among the distortions magnification rather than shrink is the problem. In most panorama equipment 25% magnification is observed.
So on the x-ray template you saw before 25% magnified implant fixtures were included. How can we use such x-ray templates? Implanted surgery is a plant for this patient in this case. Upper posterior, lower posterior visions.
Implants will be placed there bilaterally. What process did we take in the past? The first thing we had to do was to take a panorama pictures because panorama pictures were the basis of all implant procedures.
After panorama is taken, the pictures are developed and transparent paper is put over it and with sharp pencil tracing is done. By tracing, we can identify teeth, bone, maxillary sinuses, and inferior alveolar running canal.
Not only that, the regions where implants will be placed. The bone height is measured. The panorama pictures they have distorted images. It is mainly vertically distorted. Is it magnified or shrunk? It's magnified.
So 125% magnified x-ray template is shown. Before you didn't recognize it because it was whitish but it is actually transparent. The transparent paper is put over this, 125% magnified pictures are there. Implant fixtures that need to be selected feeding that height of bone. Anatomical structures that need to be avoided.
When we choose the implant fixtures maxillary sinuses or inferior alveolar canals need to be avoided when we choose the implant fixtures. Another thing, in the past panorama was very actively used because it was used for the implanted surgical stent. The stent is sometimes called a guide.
In this patient a young female patient, who received facial trauma. So many teeth were destroyed. Implant will be placed after the extraction. The positions of the implant and their relations need to be identified. Therefore, what we did was this is pre-OP.
How terrible it is. The trauma is very terrible. This is a young patient all front teeth are destroyed. She must have suffered tremendously. Maxilla is edentulous extraction was done first and this is healed after that. The casts are made like this, the missing teeth for the missing teeth. The diagnostic works up is made.
One, two, three, four, five, eight teeth are made like this. After that, over that radiologic stint is fabricated. At the region where implants will be placed. We insert metal rods one, tw,o three, four, five, six, six rods are seen here at these positions implants will be placed. After that, radiologic template or stent is or guide is removed.
And it is delivered to the patient's mouth and panorama is taken. You can see better runs, implants will be placed in those locations. The metal runs we know the length accurately.
Therefore, the degree of distortions of vertical magnification can be exactly identified. Therefore, implant diameter and length would be chosen. If implants are identified, radiologic stent, x-ray sten,t or x-ray template or guide would be removed and the metal rods are removed. The template with holes will be delivered to the mouth of a patient and the holes will guide the drilling.
This can be considered a very primitive version of the template. The one that you saw used in the digital guided implant surgery. In the past when we did not have digital or cbct. This was the most advanced technique. After surgery on the panorama, you can see implants were placed very accurately.
In the past panorama radiology, x-ray template, or radiologic template guide or stand whatever the name is. After removing the metal bronze, surgical template, surgical guide, or surgical stent was used like this absolutely necessary to use it. So I wanted to show you this immediate poster the positions are good.
And the relation with the teeth were quite accurate generating a good initial stability. So healing abutments were connected and sutured panorama can still be used quite actively and I want to emphasize this.
If you look at panorama pictures, something unfamiliar is there. Unfamiliar structure or unfamiliar condition can be seen. Please do not ignore that, that means pathologic condition.
We look at panorama almost daily. So if something is off if something is not normal. Intuitively, we can catch that so do not ignore that.
So we took the city images and ameloblastoma was found.
Panorama is very important daily procedure. Cbct is around, but still for implant surgery or surgical planning or to check the outcome of the surgery. Panorama is very important, if something is off something unfamiliar structure is observed,. We need to remember that we need to suspect that.
Lastly, standard radiology or standard periphical radiology.
Panorama x-ray picture at the upper and lower left posterior areas. Implants were placed.
If you want to look at in more details.
If you want to look at in more details, panorama is not quite sufficient. In that case, periapical x-ray can be taken. Periapical views such periapical or standard paraepical view has the advantage of detailed information is in there.
On the other hand, panorama gives broad coverage but the periodical ethical view has very limited coverage.
So the disadvantage is the information is for a limited area. Why does it give detailed information? Let's compare it to panorama view you can see clearly the difference between them periapical panorama compare them. On the x-ray, implant fixture images relation to bone teeth are shown in details.
And clearly compared to cone beam city the information is limited. The coverage of the image is restricted, that's something we have to acknowledge. We have looked at cbct panorama.
And standard periapical radiology. When we talk about x-ray images, many doctors are worried how much radiation exposure should be made and this information is necessary when we explain x-ray to our patient.
If you look at this ,the loud radiation exposure per person per year is defined as one sievert. If it is lower than that, it is considered safe and if it is over than that, it is considered a little bit risky. You can see this panorama cbct has very low level of exposure. Standard periapical would be much lower than this.
So it doesn't appear even on this diagram. When you explain this to your patients, maybe you can say this. Round trip flighted to europe has more radiation exposure than dental x-rays, that means dental x-rays are very safe procedures.
Cone beam city, cbct, or dental city is the recent digital trend. Absolutely necessary for digital dentistry. It helps for accurate surgical planning and the surgical outcome can be accurately identified using cbct. Without cbct, we cannot talk about digital. Panorama is the most basic procedure.
And it can scan the broad area through the broad scanning. Teeth, jaw bones, bone, and their relations with important anatomical structures can be identified. The bone height of the area where implants will be placed they can be identified which is very important.
After panorama pictures are taken. Further x-ray procedures can be chosen. Standard paraepical radiology has the disadvantage of limited coverage, but it gives detailed information.
Therefore, in the age of digital cbct. This is absolutely necessary.
It is meaningful to be the first to to someone.
So today will be remembered as a very important day for me because this is the day I meet you for the first time. How was it for you to be an implant master?
This is the first step. I hope you remember today as the first step. I will work hard for another encounter with you.
Thank you very much.